# Abdullah ali

**United Arab Emirates** 



abdullhali53@gmail.com



521986101



linkedin.com/in/abdullah-ali-1594b71a4

# **Summary**

An experienced and highly skilled software developer, specialized in flutter dart and front end applications development. A fast learner with solid technical background, who is capable of delivering the desired output even under pressure. Have great knowledge of web programming and technologies. A self-learner, a great problem solver and a good team player.

My journey as flutter developer started when I relocated to Dubai UAE. I'm working with a small team of developers to build an E-commerce Mobile Application. Nowadays I'm looking forward to improve my skills with the help of my co-workers to fit todays marketplace.

https://abdullah-dalallah.github.io/

# **Experience**



# Software Engineer

### **POMECHAIN**

Jul 2020 - Present (2 years 1 month +)

Flutter development

Role:

Software Development Engineer responsible for the development and support of a flagship digital wholesale platform based on the wholesale commerce. work within Agile technology teams focused on the development and roll out of features and platforms in a multi country and multi-channel environment.

### Role Summary:

- · Build wholesale Mobile Application .
- Take operational responsibility for delivery of assigned projects.
- Build communication application by using WebRTC protocol for chating, meeting.
- Communicate effectively with both technical and non-technical stakeholders.
- Support and coach teammates in monitoring and maintaining user services.
- Create a focus on high-quality code throughout the entire development process.
- implement technical best practices and standards.
- using flutter by android studio, IntelJ, Xcode, Visual studio.
- Platform & resources: Github, Stackoverflow, flutter Packages(pub.dev).
- · Experience writing automated test cases, performance tuning, threading, and offline storage
- Integrate APIs from our back-end team.
- Handling Flutter State Management Approaches/Techniques Provider and setState.

### Processes and Procedures:

- Work with multiple end user teams from the business to ascertain the business case and requirements for different features and projects.
- Communicate development progress to relevant business stakeholders.
- Adapt to a changing retail environment and recommend technologies and processes that lead to competitive advantage.

• Ensure that the system developments mirror the business capabilities in terms of merchandising and supply chain.

#### Communication:

As Software Development Engineer communicating with:

- · All Departments in order to develop platforms and rollout across Departments and Countries when
- Suppliers in order to develop platforms according to the business needs on a regular basis.



# Android - Mobile Application Developer

king abdullah university hospital jordan

May 2019 - Dec 2019 (8 months)

Developing android mobile application provide many medical services as ability to retrieve patient file through MRN, notify patient with results, provide basic chat and consults with doctors.

# **Education**



# Jordan University of Science and Technology

Bachelor's degree, Computer Software Engineering

2016 - 2020

The Department of Software Engineering at the University of Science and Technology obtained accreditation by the United Kingdom Engineering Council, as the accreditation confirmed that the program meets the standards set by the Engineering Council in the UK Standard for Professional Engineering Competence (UK-SPEC), thus becoming a software engineering graduate program. Registered with IET (Association of Engineering and Technology) and holds the title C.Eng (Certified Engineer), which is the highest accreditation a bachelor's degree program can obtain

## **Licenses & Certifications**







## Skills

Management • Software • Android Development • Data Analysis • Data Structures • Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) • User Interface Design • Programming • User Experience (UX) • Computer Science